Finding Aid of America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee Record Group SR.198
State Archives of North Carolina
- Minutes File, 1978-1986; SR.198.10; 198.10; 4048; Minutes; 1.00; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources; American Quadricentennial Corporation (Reel America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (A
  - AQC Minutes, SR.198.10; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee
    - Raleigh, 6 November 1979; SR.198.10.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Raleigh)
    - Chapel Hill, 1 March 1980; SR.198.10.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Chapel Hill)
    - Manteo, 27-28 June, 1980; SR.198.10.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Manteo)
    - Manteo, 19-20 September 1980; SR.198.10.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Manteo)
    - Greenville, 17 January 1981; SR.198.10.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Greenville)
    - Raleigh, 27 March 1981; SR.198.10.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Raleigh)
    - Manteo, 11 July 1981; SR.198.10.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Manteo)
    - Raleigh, 23 January 1982; SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Raleigh)
    - Raleigh, 4 May 1982; SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Raleigh)
    - Kill Devil Hills, 12 June 1982; SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Kill Devil Hills)
    - Charlotte, 19 March 1983; SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Charlotte)
    - Raleigh, 20 April 1983; SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Raleigh)
    - Nags Head, 18 June 1983; SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Nags Head)
    - Goldsboro, 9 September 1983; SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Goldsboro)
    - Greensboro, 3 December 1984; SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Greensboro)
    - Manteo, 22 February 1985; SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Manteo)
    - Raleigh, 8 December 1987; SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Raleigh)
  - Status Reports, SR.198.10; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee
    - January 1980, SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder January 1980)
    - January 1981, SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder January 1981)
    - June-December 1982, SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder June-December 1982)
    - January-December, 1983-1986, SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder January-December, 1983-1986)
    - January-June 1987, SR.198.10.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder January-June 1987)
- American Quadricentennial Corporation, 1978-1987, undated; SR.198.11; 198.11; Budgets; Correspondence; Minutes; 1.00; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee
  Other
  Transferred from the agency to the State Records Center, 9-21 June 2004. Transferred from the SRC to the State Archives, 9-21 June 2004.
  Correspondence, tax information, articles of incorporation, audit reports, minutes, prospectus, news clippings, questionnaire, committee information, memorandums, fundraising information, and membership information for the non-profit organization responsible for handling of all governmental and corporate grant funding as well as general public fundraising to support America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (AFHAC) objectives. This series was created from records found during move at old Capital Visitor Center file room in June 2004 and several files of H. G. Jones from Chapel Hill in 2005.
  New Series, Not on Schedule
  - Advisory Committee Questionnaire, 1982; SR.198.11.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Advisory Committee Questionnaire)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1978-1981; SR.198.11.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Articles of Incorporation)
  - Audit Reports, 1982-1986; SR.198.11.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Audit Reports)
  - Budget Report (Estimated), 1982-1987; SR.198.11.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Budget Report (Estimated))
  - Committee Activities, undated; SR.198.11.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Committee Activities)
  - Committee Information, 1979, 1984-1985, undated; SR.198.11.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Committee Information)
  - Correspondence: Carolina Telephone and Telegraph Co., 1985; SR.198.11.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Correspondence: Carolina Telephone and Telegraph Co.)
  - Correspondence: deRossett, Anne (personal), 1983-1986; SR.198.11.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Correspondence: deRossett, Anne (personal))
  - Correspondence: Fundraising (Anne deRossett), 1981-1982; SR.198.11.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Correspondence: Fundraising (Anne deRossett))
  - Correspondence: Fundraising (Anne deRossett), 1983-1987; SR.198.11.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Correspondence: Fundraising (Anne deRossett))
  - Correspondence: Macamor Foundation (Rocky Mount, NC), 1981-1982; SR.198.11.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Correspondence: Macamor Foundation (Rocky Mount, NC))
  - Correspondence: Mary Reynolds Babcock Foundation, 1982; SR.198.11.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Correspondence: Mary Reynolds Babcock Foundation)
  - Correspondence: Membership, 1980-1982, undated; SR.198.11.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Correspondence: Membership)
  - Correspondence: Warren, Lindsey, 1981-1987; SR.198.11.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Correspondence: Warren, Lindsey)
  - Correspondence: Z. Smith Reynolds Foundation, Inc., 1981-1985, undated; SR.198.11.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Correspondence: Z. Smith Reynolds Foundation, Inc.)
  - Financial Statements, 1981-1986; SR.198.11.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Financial Statements)
  - Fundraising Campaign Information, 1981-1985, undated; SR.198.11.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Fundraising Campaign Information)
  - Fundraising Luncheon: Charlotte, 22 November 1982; SR.198.11.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Fundraising Luncheon: Charlotte)
  - Fundraising Luncheon: North Wilkesboro, 25 April 1983; SR.198.11.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Fundraising Luncheon: North Wilkesboro)
  - Inventory of AQC, 1982, 1987; SR.198.11.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Inventory of AQC)
  - Memorandums, 1979, 1981-1986; SR.198.11.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Memorandums)
  - Minutes of First Meeting, 1 November 1978; SR.198.11.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Minutes of First Meeting)
  - Minutes (Miscellaneous), 1982-1983, undated; SR.198.11.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Minutes (Miscellaneous))
  - News Clippings, 1978-1980; SR.198.11.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder News Clippings)
  - Prospectus, 1981, undated; SR.198.11.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Prospectus)
  - Solicitation License Information, 1981-1987; SR.198.11.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Solicitation License Information)
  - Status Reports, 1979, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.11.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Status Reports)
- Publications, 1981-1988, undated; SR.198.12; 198.12; Books; Bound Article; 1.00; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee; American Quadricentennial Corporation
  Transferred from the agency to the State Records Center 21 April 1988. Transferred from the SRC to the Archives, 29 March 2007. Additional materials gleaned from news clippings file transferred to State Archives from North Carolina Collection at University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 6 December 2007.
  Scope and Content
  Souvenir program, booklets, historical publications, magazine articles, brochures, miscellaneous programs, newsletters, and tour information pertaining to various programs and activities of America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (AFHAC) in state, national, and international publications. This series was created from materials gleaned from news clippings file; loose materials transferred 21 April 1988; and materials found in old capital visitor center 2007.
  - America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Handbook, (souvenir program), 1984; SR.198.12.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Handbook, (souvenir program))
  - Booklets, 1982-1987, undated; SR.198.12.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Booklets)
  - Carolina Comments, 1983-1986; SR.198.12.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Carolina Comments)
  - Cumming, William P., Mapping the North Carolina Coast, 1988; SR.198.12.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Cumming, William P., Mapping the North Carolina Coast)
  - First Day Covers, 13 July 1984; SR.198.12.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder First Day Covers)
  - Friends of Elizabeth II Newsletter, 1982-1984, 1986-1987; SR.198.12.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Friends of Elizabeth II Newsletter)
  - Historic Sites, 1983-1984, undated; SR.198.12.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Historic Sites)
  - Invitations, 1982-1987, undated; SR.198.12.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Invitations)
  - Magazine Articles, 1982-1983; SR.198.12.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Magazine Articles)
  - Magazine Articles, 1984-1987, undated; SR.198.12.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Magazine Articles)
  - Native Americans, 1986, undated; SR.198.12.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Native Americans)
  - Newsletters (Miscellaneous), 1982-1987; SR.198.12.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Newsletters (Miscellaneous))
  - Operation Raleigh, 1984-1988; SR.198.12.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Operation Raleigh)
  - Press Releases, 1984-1987; SR.198.12.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Press Releases)
  - Programs and Brochures, 1982-1985; SR.198.12.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Programs and Brochures)
  - Programs and Brochures, 1986-1987, undated; SR.198.12.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Programs and Brochures)
  - Public Documents (Brochures and Posters), 1983-1987; SR.198.12.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Public Documents (Brochures and Posters))
  - Publications: Publishing Company Information, 1983-1984, undated; SR.198.12.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Publications: Publishing Company Information)
  - Publications: Quadricentennial News, 1981-1986; SR.198.12.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Publications: Quadricentennial News)
  - Publications: Raleigh and Roanoke: The British Library Exhibit, (NC Museum catalog), 1985; SR.198.12.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Publications: Raleigh and Roanoke: The British Library Exhibit, (NC Museum catalog))
  - Publications: Raleigh and Quinn: The Explorer and His Boswell, Edited by H. G. Jones, 1987; SR.198.12.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Publications: Raleigh and Quinn: The Explorer and His Boswell, Edited by H. G. Jones)
  - Publications: Telephone Directory Covers (Carolina Telephone and Telegraph Co.), 1984-1985; SR.198.12.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Publications: Telephone Directory Covers (Carolina Telephone and Telegraph Co.))
  - Publications: Tours Information, 1985, 1987; SR.198.12.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Publications: Tours Information)
  - "Lost Colony" Production Materials, 1983, 1985-1987; SR.198.12.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder "Lost Colony" Production Materials)
- Iconographic Collection, 1980-1987, undated; SR.198.13; 198.13; audio cassettes; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee; American Quadricentennial Corporation
  Audio-visual materials created in support of the activities of the America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (AFHAC).
  - Photographs to Slides, 122; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee
    - Virginia Dare Four Hundredth Birthday Commemoration, August 1987; SR.198.13.001; 300 Photographic Prints; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Virginia Dare Four Hundredth Birthday Commemoration)
    - Slides, Miscellaneous Subjects: White, John, Watercolors -- Slide Program Series I (1-59), SR.198.13.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Slides, Miscellaneous Subjects: White, John, Watercolors -- Slide Program Series I (1-59))
    - Virginia Dare Four Hundredth Birthday Commemoration, August 1987; SR.198.13.001; 300 Photographic Prints; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Virginia Dare Four Hundredth Birthday Commemoration)
    - Slides, Miscellaneous Subjects: Slide Program Series, Part I (60-90) -- Slide Series, Part II (1-25), SR.198.13.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Slides, Miscellaneous Subjects: Slide Program Series, Part I (60-90) -- Slide Series, Part II (1-25))
    - Postcard (linen), Waterside Theatre, Roanoke Island, undated; SR.198.13.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Postcard (linen), Waterside Theatre, Roanoke Island)
    - Slide Program Transcription, undated; SR.198.13.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Slide Program Transcription)
    - Slides, Miscellaneous Subjects: Fort Raleigh -- White, John, Watercolors, SR.198.13.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Slides, Miscellaneous Subjects: Fort Raleigh -- White, John, Watercolors)
    - Slides, Miscellaneous Subjects: Anniversary Cake -- Elizabeth II: Events and Celebrations, SR.198.13.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Slides, Miscellaneous Subjects: Anniversary Cake -- Elizabeth II: Events and Celebrations)
    - "Raleigh and His Visions" Flower Show at NC Museum of History, March 1985; SR.198.13.001; 3 photographic Prints; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder "Raleigh and His Visions" Flower Show at NC Museum of History)
  - Tape Recordings, 123; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee
    - AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part I), 27-28 June 1980; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part I))
    - Lecture Recordings, Dr. Crellin's Symposium on Elizabethan...Knowledge, 14 March 1985; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item Lecture Recordings, Dr. Crellin's Symposium on Elizabethan...Knowledge)
    - AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part II), 27-28 June 1980; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part II))
    - AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part I), 22 January 1982; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part I))
    - AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part II), 22 January 1982; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part II))
    - AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part I), 29 September 1984; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part I))
    - AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part II), 29 September 1984; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part II))
    - AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part III), 29 September 1984; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item AFHAC Committee Meeting Recording (Part III))
    - Lecture Recordings, Kupperman, undated; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item Lecture Recordings, Kupperman)
    - Lecture Recordings, Presentation on Elizabeth II Shipbuilding by Stanley Potter, 1981; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item Lecture Recordings, Presentation on Elizabeth II Shipbuilding by Stanley Potter)
    - Lecture Recordings, Bill Powell (side one) and George Garrett (side two), 1985; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item Lecture Recordings, Bill Powell (side one) and George Garrett (side two))
    - Lecture Recordings, Jeanne Holgate and last part of Helen Wallis talk, 11 March 1985; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item Lecture Recordings, Jeanne Holgate and last part of Helen Wallis talk)
    - Lecture Recordings, Horace Whitfield, 13 March 1985; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item Lecture Recordings, Horace Whitfield)
    - Lecture Recordings, Helen Wallis and Peter Barger, 8 March 1985; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item Lecture Recordings, Helen Wallis and Peter Barger)
    - Lecture Recordings, Helen Wallis, 11 March 1985; SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item Lecture Recordings, Helen Wallis)
    - Lecture Recordings, Unidentified Recordings, SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item Lecture Recordings, Unidentified Recordings)
    - Lecture Recordings, Unidentified+G2:G30 Recordings, SR.198.13.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Item Lecture Recordings, Unidentified+G2:G30 Recordings)